ZIAD HOSNY

FULL STACK DEVELOPER ziadhosny007@gmail.com

(+2) 01110146112



ziadhosny.vercel.app



<u>LinkedIn</u>



GitHub



Egypt

PROFILE

I have 2+ years of Experience in Analyzing, Designing, Developing and Integrating Front-End & Back-End based applications. Experience in developing application using TypeScript, React, ReactNative, NodeJs, Express. Seeking a role as Front-end and Nodejs Developer

EXPERIENCE

Jul 2022 - Jun 2023

Bitspire Company - Full stack Developer (React And Nodejs).

Developing frontend and backend websites using React, Node and I am responsible for developing new features and user interfaces from wireframe models, ensuring the best performance and user experience of the software, fixing bugs and performance problems, writing clean, readable, and testable code, cooperating with back-end developers, designers,

Dec 2022 - Mar 2023

eSmart Company - Front-end Developer.

responsible for Creating And Developing a calendar for the clinic system by picking and rescheduling suitable dates for doctors' appointments.

SKILLS

- React

- NodeJs

- JavaScript

- TypeScript

- Docker

- React Native

- Tailwind CSS

- CSS

- Angular

- Bootstrap

- Firebase

- SASS

- postgresql

- MongoDB

- Git

- Express

- CI-CD

- Python

EDUCATION

Apr 2022 - Sep 2022

Information Technology Institute

Front-End & Cross-Platform Intensive Code Camp

2016 - 2020

Mansoura University

BSc in Computers and Information - Mansoura University. (Grade: Very Good). Graduation Project: Building a mobile learning app with a chatbot by Android, Java, Python, and NLP.

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Self Learning

- Team Work

- Problem solving

- Continuous improvement

- Good communication

PROJECTS

Portfolio





- My personal portfolio to show my progress, skills, and my latest projects, You can contact me through it. Build Using NextJs, TypeScript, React, MUI, CSS

Advanced Audio Player



- Full project for playing audios and soundtracks, Play audios randomly or on repeat. with a cool feature that makes you select a specific part of the audio and insert the number of times you want to play it, log in, and make your favorite list.

Build using GatsbyJs, React, Node, Express, Postgresql, Sass

Scheduler



- React And JS Library Calender for clinic System by picking and rescheduling dates for doctors' appointments by Inserting or dragging dates, Adding more information about the date, and disabling holidays, which is suitable for any booking system with high performance and easy-to-use features.

Build using React, Typescript, Javascript, date-fns, MUI

• Task Manager



- Full Task Manager with a Nice user interface in which you can add, check tasks, and pick due dates for accomplishing tasks with filter, Edit, and delete features.

Build using React, Redux, Node, MongoDB, Express, MUI, CSS

• Freshio





- ITI Graduation project E-commerce for buying healthy products and protein supplies, With Categories and filters to pick products according to price and Calories per product, I was the team leader who designed and chose the suitable solutions for this project with high-performance and maintainable software.

Build using React, MUI, Bootstrap, and Firebase.

Netflix





- Building Netflix Clone using React, tailwindcss, and Firebase.

LANGUAGES

- English : Professional

- Arabic : Native